Jack: In general, the world has
become a place where most people
communicate in short sound bites
limited by word counts via social media.
It is easier to communicate via
text than to engage in conversation.
Verbal communication styles have
subsequently had to adapt to meet
these restrictions by being clear and
concise to get a message over quickly.
However, some messages are more
complicated and cannot be communicated
in that way but can still be
explained clearly and concisely.
They also must be interesting enough to
engage the listener and informative enough
to enable the listener to understand.
Leah: One way of engaging listeners
is to take a storytelling approach
to put a message into context.
Learning to express information as a
story can help to draw the listeners
in by having a beginning a middle and
an end, rather than just expressing
a list of facts and information.
Even introducing characters and
scenarios can make it more interesting.
Using metaphors and analogies can
also help put across complex messages
that may not be easy to explain.
They can also link it to something that
the listener may be more accustomed
Jack: to.
Using visual aids can also help with
presentations to demonstrate ideas,
give examples and reinforce information.
A clear and easy to understand speaking
voice can help engage listeners and
keep them actively listening, especially
knowing when to change tone and
inflection and pausing for reactions.
One of the
Leah: most important things when
presenting information and ideas is
to be prepared and plan what is to be
communicated verbally, whether this is by
use of cue cards or visual presentation.
Otherwise, important information
may be omitted or misrepresented
with potentially damaging effects.